CHARLES BRANDON KILGORE

Atlanta, GA

Phone: 478-251-6961 Email: Brandonk1023@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-kilgore-69695b135 GitHub: https://github.com/Brandonk1023

SUMMARY

Passionate and solutions-driven web developer who is completing a full stack web development certificate from Georgia Tech. Experience in tech support utilizing a combination of strong communication, collaboration, problem-solving, and analytical skills. Strong ability to learn, design, build, and maintain websites. I have experience working in a fast-paced and diverse team environment collaborating to achieve team goals. I have strong interest in backend technology, application security, cloud technology, and mobile technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Softwares/Platforms/Tools</u>: jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, GitHub, BootStrap, Handlebars, MongoDB, npm, Insomnia, VS Code, Heroku, Sequelize, REACT

<u>Software Languages</u>: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Operating Systems: Windows, Debian Linux, Mac

PROJECT EXAMPLES

FoodWillBeerUsApart: https://github.com/Brandonk1023/FoodWillBeerUsApart Deployed Project: https://stbuiemory.github.io/FoodWillBeerUsApart/

- An application that provides an easy to use tool for beer and food pairing. The user can also save their favorite beer and food pairings for quick reference.
- Researched API's and their implementation, assisted with JavaScript functionality
- Tech: jQuery, Bulma, Punk API, Pexel API, JavaScript, HTML.

Express-Note-Taker: https://github.com/Brandonk1023/Express-Note-Taker Deployed Project: https://rocky-harbor-14327.herokuapp.com/

- A simple application that a user can use to store, delete, and edit notes for reviewing later.
- created backend routes, connected the front end
- Tech:Express, Heroku, JavaScript, npm, node

Pot It Like It's Hot: https://github.com/stbuiemory/2kPerDay Deployed Project: Currently In Progress

- An application that allows users to look at the care requirements of different types of plants and add them to their online collection. The users are then prompted when it is time to water their plants with reminders in their garden screen.
- Created backend routes, researching API and implementation, Implementation of Passport for authentication. Assisting with frontend JavaScript code as needed
- Tech:Passport, Express, npm, Heroku, Perennial API, Node, Handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, node

EXPERIENCE

Cox Automotive 2022-CURRENT

Dealer Concierge II/Customer Care Specialist II

- Provide tier one support for customer request
- Troubleshoot technology issues for products/solutions
- Provide training on products to dealers and sales
- Identify patterns to find possible product/technology defects
- Diagnose technology related issues
- Provided coaching on products to team members

Farmers Insurance - Tettleton Agency 2020-2021

Customer Service Representative

- Provided first contact support for customer requests
- Helped diagnose/resolve customer tech/support issues
- Helped educate/determine customer coverage needs
- Quoted new and current business
- Worked event booths to bring in potential customers

Brandon Kilgore Photography 2013-CURRENT

Freelance Photographer

- Provided photographic coverage for client events/portraits
- Worked on multiple personal documentary Projects
- Cataloged artwork/events for Georgia Southern Art Dept.
- 2017 Betty Foy Sanders Scholarship Winner

KEH CAMERA INC 2020-2020

Camera Technician

- Tested/graded/repaired photographic equipment
- Recorded issues/data for repair and grading purposes

Triumph Aero-Structures 2019-2020

Tooling/Procurement Planner 2019-2020 | Assembly 2013-2015

- Worked with vendors on pricing and lead-time improvements
- Assisted with rebuild of inventory system
- Responsible for cultivating vendor relationships
- Maintained inventory and planning of tools and materials
- Solved tooling issues with production to meet goals/deadlines
- Lead Tool-Crib Team to support productions needs
- Assisted with tool setup, troubleshoot, and repair
- Read and followed blueprint specs to assemble parts
- Worked on tight deadlines to finish parts for shipment

Georgia Southern Shooting Sports Center 2015-2018

Range Master 2016-2018 | Range Safety Officer 2015-2016

- Maintained operations, equipment, and safety of the range
- Created/collaborated on documents used for range operation
- Managed team to accomplish goals and operations of facility
- Responsible for coaching classes and running tournaments
- Screened individuals seeking membership

EDUCATION

Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp: Georgia Tech, Atlanta, GA IN-PROGRESS

- A fast paced, intense 24 week program on fullstack web development.
- Provided experience live-coding and collaborating with peers
- Attained structured, hands on experience coding for full stack development.
- Training on backend and front end technologies.

P&C Insurance License (#3402472): Georgia Dept. of Insurance, Atlanta, GA 2021

BA of Studio Art, Minor of Marketing: Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, GA 2015 – 2018

AS of General Studies: Georgia Military College, Milledgeville, GA 2010 – 2013

High School Diploma: Baldwin High School, Milledgeville, GA 2006 – 2010